denim a brand new way to write server-side JavaScript it solves many of
denim 一种编写服务器端 JavaScript 的全新方法，它解决了许多
the same problems as nodejs and was even created by the same guy like node it
与 nodejs 相同的问题，甚至是由像 node 这样的人创建的，它在底层
uses the v8 JavaScript engine under the hood but the rest of the runtime is
使用 v8 JavaScript 引擎，但运行时的其余部分
implemented in rust and typescript our journey into denna land begins in a
是在 rust 和 typescript 我们进入 denna 领域的旅程
single type script file in this file we have access to all the types in the
始于此文件中的单个类型脚本文件我们可以访问运行时中的所有类型，
runtime which means we can write strongly typed code and get
这意味着我们可以直接在 IDE 中编写强类型代码并获取
documentation and intellisense directly in the IDE without ever needing to touch
文档和智能感知，而无需
a TS config file the features in the runtime can be accessed from this demo
接触 TS 配置文件运行时中的功能可以从这个演示
namespace let's console.log the current working directory of the filesystem we
命名空间访问让我们控制台记录文件系统的当前工作目录我们
can execute our script with demo run from the command line but you'll notice
可以从命令行使用演示运行我们的脚本但是你会
the throws an error and that's because demo is secure by default you the
注意到抛出一个错误，这是因为演示 默认情况下是安全的，您
developer need to give permission to perform different actions in the runtime
开发人员需要授予在运行时执行不同操作的权限，
in this case we can use the allow read flag to allow this operation security is
在这种情况下，我们可以使用允许读取标志来允许此操作安全 ity
great but my favorite thing is how everything asynchronous is promise based
很棒，但我最喜欢的是所有异步都是基于承诺的，
we can make a network request using the fetch API just like we would in the
我们可以像在
browser and because it supports top-level wait we don't even need an
浏览器中一样使用 fetch API 发出网络请求，因为它支持顶级等待，我们甚至不需要
async function here we can start resolving promises without any extra
异步函数 可以在没有任何额外样板代码的情况下开始解决承诺
boilerplate code denno attempts to make your code as browser compatible as
denno 尝试使您的代码尽可能与浏览器兼容
possible it contains a window object with lifecycle events that you can
它包含一个带有生命周期事件的窗口对象，您可以
listen to allowing developers to more easily write code that can interrupt
收听它允许开发人员更轻松地编写可以
between browsers and servers not to mention it can also execute web assembly
在浏览器和服务器之间中断的代码，更不用说 它还可以执行 Web 程序集
binaries but one thing that won't work in demo are your NPM packages instead
二进制文件，但在演示中不起作用的一件事是你的 NPM 包，而不是
you import packages using the modern yes module syntax with remote modules being
你使用现代 yes 模块语法导入包，
referenced by their URL when you run your script for the first time it will
当你第一次运行脚本时，远程模块由它们的 URL 引用它会
download this code locally and cache it there's no package JSON and code can be
在本地下载此代码并缓存它没有 JSON 包，并且可以
referenced from any URL very similar to how things work in the browser demo
从任何 URL 引用代码，这与事情的工作方式非常相似 浏览器演示
provides a set of standard modules to solve common use cases for example we
提供了一组标准模块来解决常见用例，例如我们
can import serve from the HTTP module we can use it to create a server that's
可以从 HTTP 模块导入 serve 我们可以使用它来创建一个
treated as an async iterable we can then await every request from the server and
被视为异步迭代的服务器，然后我们可以等待来自服务器的每个请求并
respond to it accordingly and that's an awesome starting point for a server-side
响应它 因此，对于服务器端 JavaScript 应用程序来说，这是一个很棒的起点，
JavaScript app now then au 1.0 just hit release candidate 1 so if you start
然后 au 1.0 刚刚发布候选版本 1，所以如果你
using it today consider yourself an early adopter do
今天开始使用它，认为自己是早期采用者，
you think denno is the future of server-side JavaScript let me know in
你认为 denno 是服务器端 JavaScript 的未来吗？让我知道 在
the comments below thanks for watching hit the like button and I will see you
下面的评论中感谢您的观看点击喜欢按钮，我会在下一个看到你
in the next one